中文字幕
All right, this is CS50, and this is, sadly, the end,
where we wrap up the semester and take a look back at the past several weeks,
中文字幕
give you a look at what's ahead in the next several weeks,
and then really the next several years, how you can sort of go on,
中文字幕
beyond CS50, with the proverbial training wheels now completely off.
And so that even without things like CS50 IDE, and Check 50,
中文字幕
and Help 50, and other such tools, you actually
feel like you can apply all of these lessons learned, and all of these tools
中文字幕
you've experienced in CS50 to your own Macs and PCs in the real world.
But I thought it would be perhaps helpful or reassuring, especially
中文字幕
on the heels of so many problems sets, some of them especially challenging,
and a recent quiz here on campus, to just think back at this tenant here.
中文字幕
And we do mean this.
And realize if you're a little uneasy as to what
中文字幕
remains in store for the next few weeks, that
what ultimately matters in this course is not so much
中文字幕
where you end up relative to your classmates,
but where you end up in week 10, which is today, relative to yourself
中文字幕
in week zero, some 10 weeks ago.
So that was just a bold claim, a pie in the sky back then.
中文字幕
But you've made it to this now finish line, where all that remains
is that one final milestone, where there's no specification.
中文字幕
You're not told what to do, but you get to design and implement yourself.
And consider too, over the past several weeks,
中文字幕
odds are many of you never really felt like you got your footing, like ever.
Just as you started to grasp something, we sort of pulled the rug out
中文字幕
from under you, or kind of asked you to take another step up cognitively,
and actually understand something new.
中文字幕
Well, that's very much the design of this.
I was trying to think of metaphors yesterday.
中文字幕
And if you're into like weight lifting or such, which I'm not,
I suppose the analog here might be you're
中文字幕
sort of doing your weight lifting and someone
keeps putting more and more weight on the thing as you get better and better.
中文字幕
And so you never actually necessarily feel
like you're making progress, because it never gets any easier.
中文字幕
But that's just because the weight on either end is,
so I'm told, is getting added to and added to.
中文字幕
And I do mean that more academically here too,
is that with every passing week, we start
中文字幕
to hope that you were reasonably comfortable with what was in the past,
so that we could lead you further along in that journey.
中文字幕
And perhaps most stark is the fact that 10 weeks ago, many of you
probably found this difficult, right?
中文字幕
It's probably not all that distant a memory how many minutes, or hours,
or a few days that it actually took just to get Mario, so to speak--
中文字幕
and Mario's not even in the picture--
to just ascend this kind of pyramid by using hashtags.
中文字幕
And honestly, just a week ago, did you all
build this, CS50 finance, which had a back end implemented
中文字幕
in Python, generating HTML and CSS dynamically,
that was talking to a front end, that itself
中文字幕
was built with client-side languages, like HTML, and CSS, and JavaScript,
talking meanwhile to an API, via HTTP, that brought in data from a third party
中文字幕
source.
Like, that's where you now are.
中文字幕
And so even if you don't feel 100% like you could build this from scratch,
and that's fine, indeed what many students do for their final project is
中文字幕
start with something like P Set 8, tear out all the finance specific stuff,
and then start to add their own thoughts, and ideas,
中文字幕
and their own code, notice just what the Delta truly is.
And that's what we mean by that Delta between week zero and week 10.
中文字幕
I received, just this past week, actually, an email
from one of your classmates, who I thought
中文字幕
was wonderfully reflective on what their experience had been like.
And quite consistent with this idea of not quite ever getting their footing,
中文字幕
wrote this, "Besides learning the new material,
I felt that I started to be more comfortable with being
中文字幕
uncomfortable and being OK with working towards building a skill,
rather than getting the right answer."
中文字幕
This is the kind of quote that you kind of see
in like a Harvard brochure or whatnot, but it's like, it really is true,
中文字幕
this idea of being comfortable being uncomfortable is very much the case.
And honestly, you're never really going to get your footing in this world.
中文字幕
Because honestly, everything we just taught this past semester
is going to evolve, starting tomorrow, and in the years to come.
中文字幕
But hopefully, what we've done in the class,
by choosing certain languages, some of the most foundational, like C,
中文字幕
and SQL, and now Python, even as those languages evolve themselves,
or become less used, the principles of memory management,
中文字幕
and data structures, and tradeoffs, and abstraction, and encapsulation, all
of those principles, those aren't going away.
中文字幕
And that's the advantage, I think, of starting from the so-called ground up.
It wasn't that long ago we were talking about zeros and ones.
中文字幕
So you're not just software engineers, you're
computer scientists, or budding computer scientists,
中文字幕
because you have those mental models that
can then be applied to any new technologies or domains that
中文字幕
are down the road.
And if it's reassuring too, even I feel this way.
中文字幕
Like, I don't feel like I've mastered CS50 or all of the material therein.
I kind of feel like that graph that we drew,
中文字幕
that was that green curved line, where like,
fortunately, I'm always making some forward progress,
中文字幕
but I'm never actually reaching the peak of anything,
because there's always something new to learn.
中文字幕
And it's scary, too.
And, in fact, the most relevant instance of being
中文字幕
comfortable being uncomfortable, or maybe if in my case,
being uncomfortable being uncomfortable, was just a few years ago.
中文字幕
For many years, CS50 had used a language called PHP for the web programming
portion of the course.
中文字幕
And eventually, we as the staff, decided it's time to transition
to Python, which has a number of upsides.
中文字幕
Among them, the applicability in the real world.
It can be used more effectively for command line
中文字幕
programs, data science, data analytics, and it just felt like it was time.
The one to catch was I didn't know Python.
中文字幕
And so this sounded like a wonderful idea, sort of philosophically,
that summer, yes, we shall teach Python this fall.
中文字幕
Then October came around, and I realized,
oh, Python's coming up in a week or two, we should probably, we, meaning I,
中文字幕
should probably go learn Python.
And so that entire semester, was I learning,
中文字幕
and we're repaving the road as we went.
And I swear, if you look back at the videos from just a few years ago,
中文字幕
the Python lecture was like the longest lecture ever we have.
Because I was so damn determined to prove to everyone that I knew Python
中文字幕
by that point in the semester.
So perhaps overcompensating a little bit.
中文字幕
But this is just to reassure that none of us
even the smartest of your teaching fellows and CAs, whom
中文字幕
you interacted with this year, and myself, like none of us
ever stop learning or stop being a little uncomfortable with this stuff.
中文字幕
So even if you feel like, wow, I didn't quite absorb everything this semester,
you weren't ever going to, because we never did either.
中文字幕
So take that to heart if you would.
Before we forge ahead-- oh, in fact, I thought I'd mentioned to,
中文字幕
don't aspire to build this, for instance, mirrored
backgrounds kind of went out of vogue a long, long, long time ago.
中文字幕
But this was the first example of me building something, or trying
to solve a problem, that I had no idea how to do.
中文字幕
CS50 at the time did not teach web programming.
CS51 at the time did not teach web programming,
中文字幕
did not teach Perl, or CSV files, or the kind of ingredients
I needed to build this, or even HTML or CSS for that--
中文字幕
actually, there was no CSS at that time, or even HTML.
And so for me, too, this was an example of being
中文字幕
comfortable being uncomfortable, just volunteering I will build the Frosh I
Am's website, and then turning to my roommate,
中文字幕
and saying, how am I going to build the Frosh I Am's website,
and just getting comfortable with that idea.
中文字幕
You'll figure it out.
And honestly, the key secret is to just surround yourself
中文字幕
by really smart, smarter people, who know way more than you,
who are more comfortable than you, so you can stand on their shoulders
中文字幕
and learn from them along the way.
And indeed, allow me to thank, before we forge ahead, just a few
中文字幕
of the folks that you've either seen or not seen,
especially those behind the scenes here today,
中文字幕
Mike, and Luke, and Jose, and Tom, who, with media services,
have helped us with all of this amazing stuff over the past year.
中文字幕
CS50's production team, Dan and Tara, and Ian, and Andrew, a couple of whom
are new this year.
中文字幕
And I know they were really thrown into the fire.
You see one of them too, Max, the guy who's creepily got a camera on his head
中文字幕
today here-- oh, OK, who doesn't at the moment--
on our production team as well, all helped capture this.
中文字幕
And you'll see too, even this world, of videos influenced by software,
this other camera here, that's just robotically been going back and forth,
中文字幕
left to right all semester, controlled essentially by a PS4 controller,
via software and via a Wi-Fi connection thereto.
中文字幕
So thank you to the team for making possible so many of the experiences you
all have had here online.
中文字幕
And of course, there's a whole bigger team
teaching the class, the CAs, and the TFs, our preceptors,
中文字幕
and the heads of the class, without whom I certainly could not do this.
These are all of their names there, sandwiched in.
中文字幕
And perhaps if we could, and we'll let them
know by playing the video for them, such a round
中文字幕
of applause that they got here at lecture is thanks for their time
with us this year.
中文字幕
If we could.
In particular, you might have noticed the notes
中文字幕
that are on the course's website, usually a couple of days
after the lecture.
中文字幕
And this is all thanks to a former teaching
fellow, Cheng Gong, who graduated a few years ago in computer science,
中文字幕
and has wonderfully continue to watch the course's videos, just
a few hours, typically, after they air, so as to provide you
中文字幕
with a canonical set of notes, so that you're not yourselves,
heads down, scribbling everything down.
中文字幕
Cheng, therefore, is going to be hearing and listening to these very words.
And therefore, I've been told to say just what a wonderful person Chang
中文字幕
Gong is, and how we couldn't do the course so well without him,
and we really forever appreciate all of his contributions to CS50,
中文字幕
and he would make a wonderful addition to any tech company out there.
So, thank you.
中文字幕
Thank you to Chang, as well.
And allow me to call out a couple of folks
中文字幕
in particular, two of our undergrads, who among the most involved
in the course, behind the scenes and in front of the scenes.
中文字幕
One of whom is in the process of translating the course into Spanish
with us, so that we can make it available not only to students here,
中文字幕
but also natively to folks elsewhere in the world for whom
English is a second, or not even, a third language.
中文字幕
And therefore, the English aspects of the class despite,
its being open courseware, are just an unnecessary hurdle,
中文字幕
in terms of the software, and the content, and so forth.
And so, in fact, I thought I'd give you a glimpse
中文字幕
of what CS50's own Veronica has been doing over the past few months.
For instance, this is what awaits students online soon,
中文字幕
as they, themselves, tackle, just as the Myla helped us here in English, Mario,
for instance.
中文字幕
VERONICA: [SPEAKING SPANISH]
SPEAKER 1: My thanks to other folks behind the scenes, some of whom
中文字幕
you might have met, Aaron, and Greg, and Doug, and then one other member
of the course's heads, who sadly, will be graduating this coming spring.
中文字幕
Brian Yu literally wandered into my office a few years ago.
And we got to chatting about whether he could get
中文字幕
involved in some form in the course.
And here now, three or so years later, he spent January's with us,
中文字幕
summers here with us, and pretty much runs the show now.
And honestly, of all of the head teaching fellows we've had, all of them
中文字幕
are amazing, but there really is something special about Brian Yu.
And honestly, in a word, he is extraordinary.
中文字幕
And what I thought we'd do is, as thanks to the staff,
and as an invitation to you all, to consider applying to join us as a TF,
中文字幕
as a CA, as a photographer, as a producer, any number of hats
that the team here wears, we filmed in advance, thanks to CS50's production
中文字幕
team, and thanks CS50's own Connor Doyle, and undergrad,
put together the following film that Brian has beautifully introduced us to.
中文字幕
And then we'll take a quick look back at some of our volunteers
who have appeared here in lectures past on stage, CS50 Puzzle Day
中文字幕
lunches, and more, as a bit of reflection on where you've all
come this past year.
中文字幕
If we could dim the lights again.
And off [INAUDIBLE]
中文字幕
(SINGING) Help me out, let me down.
I could learn from you, I could learn from you.
中文字幕
Help me out, let me down.
I could learn from you.
中文字幕
So if we could, a round of applause again for the staff.
So let's take a quick look back then at what
中文字幕
it meant to be 10 weeks ago, when we tore, and I was actually just thinking,
we probably should have added the meme clip to that part of the video here,
中文字幕
we tore this phone book in half and began our discussion
of computational thinking and all things thereafter.
中文字幕
And what we hope to do with this quick look,
is to just remind you just how far, truly, you've come,
中文字幕
and to sort of remind how hopefully a number of these topics
have all coincided and intermingled.
中文字幕
So this was computer science, right?
In week zero, we proposed this black box, that we revealed to be algorithms.
中文字幕
And we had inputs and outputs.
We needed to represent those inputs and outputs, and thus
中文字幕
were it was born zeros, and ones, and binary.
And from there, did we talk about higher level abstractions,
中文字幕
talking about how you might have decimal or letters of the alphabet, ASCII
and Unicode, the number 65, representing the same there,
中文字幕
the same pattern of bits might represents something like a dot,
or a pixel of yellow.
中文字幕
If you have a whole bunch of those dots or pixels,
you might have a crying face of joy.
中文字幕
And if you might have multiple images like that,
you might have animojis or videos, more generally,
中文字幕
which are just yet another abstraction on top of that.
And so, as you go out into the real world now, after CS50,
中文字幕
and see pretty fancy and newfangled technologies,
just start to critique them in your mind.
中文字幕
And consider, well, I know how this feature is done,
and I know how that feature implements that feature.
中文字幕
Odds are, you can reverse engineer in your mind how many
of today's technologies work, just by building
中文字幕
backwards to those lower levels.
We then introduced pseudo-codes, so we could
中文字幕
talk about what it meant to express yourself
more carefully, more methodically.
中文字幕
And we introduced loops, and conditions, and variables,
and other such tenants, that we then translated,
中文字幕
eventually to another language.
And we also talked not about correctness, but about efficiency.
中文字幕
So that you have a mental model of just how good your code, or your algorithm,
or your thought ultimately is.
中文字幕
And then was introduced Scratch, so that you
had a way, albeit graphically, to express
中文字幕
all of these various components, by programming Scratch up and down,
and left and right.
中文字幕
Of course, things got pretty scary, or ugly, pretty quickly.
We then transitioned to C, when all of a sudden, the simplest of "Hello world,"
中文字幕
started to look like that.
Odds are, that first week, if you'd never seen any programming
中文字幕
language before, let alone C, most of those lines
did not look familiar, except for perhaps the "Hello world,"
中文字幕
but even that thing was followed by some random backslash n.
And all of that have we, hopefully, teased apart over the past many weeks.
中文字幕
That, of course, gets compiled down to zeros and ones,
which the computer only understands.
中文字幕
And thankfully, we humans live in an age where
we don't need to worry about that level, or relatively few
中文字幕
of us do, because we have abstractions, and libraries,
and other developments on top.
中文字幕
In week two, did we then introduce other aspects of programming,
and functions, and return values, and the like.
中文字幕
And we also talked about what's really going on underneath the hood.
Code, like this here, for instance, gets compiled often
中文字幕
into multiple files, CS50s, standard iOS and your own code,
and then they all get linked together.
中文字幕
But there too, that's what you're getting for free,
so to speak, by running a compiler like Clang, albeit again
中文字幕
and again, whenever you make a change to your code.
We introduced the notion of memory, a little chip that
中文字幕
might be in your computer.
And if we zoom in on that, it really is just
中文字幕
this beautiful, simple canvas of bytes, top to bottom,
left to right, that you can do anything you want with.
中文字幕
Like that is it.
Despite all of the seeming complexity of a computer,
中文字幕
that is the canvas that you have to work with.
And that was allowing us to do any number of the data structures
中文字幕
and algorithms on top of it.
For instance, in week three, we talked about strings.
中文字幕
And strings were very straightforward.
You might not have heard the word initially
中文字幕
in the context of programming, but just a sequence of characters,
like a word, a phrase, a sentence, or such.
中文字幕
And then things got scary again quickly, when we said,
those are a little bit of a white lie, and abstraction,
中文字幕
more properly, on top of pointers.
Of course, pointers themselves got a little scary quickly.
中文字幕
And even in retrospect, this might still look scary.
And that's fine.
中文字幕
The reality most of you will not have occasion to program in C again.
The only occasions I have are generally in September and October of every year,
中文字幕
myself, because in the real world, I tend not to use this language,
though it does remain super popular and super commonly used,
中文字幕
especially in hardware based contexts, where you really
want to squeeze as much performance as possible out of the hardware,
中文字幕
and you don't necessarily want the overhead of a higher level language,
like Python.
中文字幕
But what's important is just those principles.
The fact that you can put things in memory, you can go there,
中文字幕
you can move them.
That's all this crazy syntax has been doing for us.
中文字幕
Of course, it didn't end well for Binky, when you abused this.
And indeed a lot of today's programming errors, even
中文字幕
ones that are still with us today, reduce to misusing or accidentally
touching memory that you should not.
中文字幕
But once you have that primitive, this ability to stitch things together
in memory, then you can start to build things in software.
中文字幕
We introduced Structs, in C, which allow us to come up with our own custom data
types that have multiple things inside of them.
中文字幕
And once you have that, if one of those things
is itself a pointer to something else, you
中文字幕
can kind of string things together in memory,
thereby giving you access to linked lists, which solve problems when
中文字幕
it comes to the limitations of arrays.
And you can do even fancier things like hash tables, that might conceptually
中文字幕
and pictorial look like this, or even the crazier
tri, which theoretically, is even more efficient,
中文字幕
it just takes up so much more space.
But that's it.
中文字幕
With pointers, all you're doing is stitching these data structures
together.
中文字幕
And even though most languages on top of C, like Python, and Java, and PHP,
and Ruby, don't have pointers per se, they
中文字幕
have the idea of addresses or references still.
So the concept is there, they've just made it a little easier
中文字幕
not to shoot yourself in the foot by making mistakes and getting things
like seg fault. The compilers and the interpreters
中文字幕
are increasingly getting good at helping you protect yourself from human error.
And then, thereafter, we began to transition, felt like a long time in C,
中文字幕
but we began to talk about HTTP, and virtual envelopes and messages,
just going from point A to point B. And among those things were headers.
中文字幕
And you'll recall, perhaps among the more amusing headers,
was this one, bought some years ago.
中文字幕
If you use a browser or if you use Curl, like a program at the command
line, and the IDE, or your Mac or PC, and you actually request this,
中文字幕
what was the status code that came back?
Anyone recall?
中文字幕
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
SPEAKER 1: Wasn't 200, wasn't 404.
中文字幕
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
SPEAKER 1: Yeah, it was like permanently redirected.
中文字幕
I think 301 or 302 came back, and where did it lead to?
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Yale University.
So that was nice and fun.
中文字幕
Of course, they bought HarvardSucks.org some time ago.
And for those unfamiliar, this weekend is,
中文字幕
of course, the Harvard-Yale football game, here in Cambridge this year.
So as clever as Yale has been for like a decade of paying annually
中文字幕
for, or rather as clever as we have been, whoever the alum,
is paying for a decade for Safetyschool.org
中文字幕
redirecting to Yale.edu, unfortunately, HarvardSucks.org also lives on.
In fact, there's a whole wonderful back story there,
中文字幕
that was about 12-plus years ago now.
Where some enterprising students at Yale kind of really got us.
中文字幕
Have folks seen or heard this story?
So we really embarrassed ourselves some years ago.
中文字幕
And it will all boil down to some very enterprising Yale students
using a little bit of software and a computer program
中文字幕
to create an actual bitmap, like a grid of pixels using humans.
The problem was that those humans were us, on the Harvard side,
中文字幕
in the Harvard stadium.
Because we essentially created a bitmap message, thanks to their cleverness.
中文字幕
So I thought we'd dim the lights and for about three minutes,
look at just how bad they got us.
中文字幕
Now to be fair, we got them for like 12 years, or 19 years of football
thereafter, though they have been winning the past couple of years.
中文字幕
So we can't really talk about this now.
So without further ado, let's dim the lights and pull this look up too.
中文字幕
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
- We're headed up to Boston, checking out the stadium for a prank.
中文字幕
- A few years ago, I was at a math conference.
And I was sitting around at the table at dinner,
中文字幕
with a few other mathematicians.
And one of them went to Harvard, and started
中文字幕
telling the story of this amazing prank that was against Harvard.
And at that point, I felt I had to interrupt,
中文字幕
and said, well, actually I can tell you a lot more about that.
- OK.
中文字幕
- The idea was perfected in a dorm room.
- We came up with the idea, actually, to prank them
中文字幕
with signs at the football game.
We threw some ideas out there as far as what the signs would say.
中文字幕
We eventually settled on "We Suck."
and my immediate reaction was, no, this will never work.
中文字幕
However, the problem solver in me started thinking, well, maybe we
can make this work.
中文字幕
- The problem, they had to infiltrate Harvard stadium without getting caught,
sneak in 1,800 placards, distribute them to unsuspecting Harvard fans,
中文字幕
and then convince those fans to prank themselves.
- That's great.
中文字幕
- We thought about basically every possible thing that could go wrong
and tried to come up with a solution for it.
中文字幕
- And then you put two guys on top of it.
- They made fake Harvard IDs and fake backstories, fake placard designs,
中文字幕
and a 28-member fake pep squad.
On November 20th, 2004, the fake Harvard students
中文字幕
smuggled the placards into the game.
- What do you think of Yale, sir?
中文字幕
- They suck.
- It's not going to say something like Yale sucks, is it?
中文字幕
- It says go Harvard.
- But then, trouble.
中文字幕
- What houses are you guys in?
- That's not a real house.
中文字幕
- Ho-fo?
- Yeah.
中文字幕
- You guys aren't from Harvard, are you?
- Can I see your Harvard ID because I really think you guys are from Yale.
中文字幕
- I just showed him the front of this ID,
and all the sudden, he just ran away, and he felt so embarrassed.
中文字幕
- Having escaped one confrontation, they couldn't risk another.
It was time.
中文字幕
- This just looks like a total mess.
- We have absolutely no idea if this is going to work.
中文字幕
- Look at them, they have the paper.
It's actually going to happen.
中文字幕
I can't [BEEP] believe this.
- What was once a prank, became a legend.
中文字幕
- We did it.
- And immediately, we started hearing chants from the other side.
中文字幕
You suck.
- You suck, you suck, you suck.
中文字幕
- And I think it was at that point in time that we knew we had pulled it off.
- One more time.
中文字幕
- There it goes again.
- I really think it didn't matter that Harvard
中文字幕
won, because of the prank for a lot of Yale students and alumni,
we definitely won that year.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: So there you go problem solving at Harvard, Yale as well.
All right, the bar has been set.
中文字幕
So thereafter, let's try to somehow make this more academic
again, so thereafter, did we transition from looking at the principles of HTTP,
中文字幕
and the envelopes with which you can send messages,
and actually introduced a language with which
中文字幕
we can create user interfaces and things far more interesting
than terminal windows alone.
中文字幕
Of course, there was a connection even to the material past,
because underneath the hood, what your browser is
中文字幕
doing is reading that HTML, top to bottom, left to right,
and building really a tree structure in memory,
中文字幕
that you can then manipulate using JavaScript, yet another language.
And then in week six, did we tragically point out
中文字幕
that all that complexity we'd wrestled with just a few weeks ago,
trying to build a linked list with null at the end and pointers throughout,
中文字幕
actually reduces to just this in Python, just a single line of code.
And then this amazing data structure that theoretically
中文字幕
has constant time access and dynamic growth,
because you can chain everything off of it.
中文字幕
You just have to write a lot of code to do all the memory management,
is just this in Python.
中文字幕
But underneath the hood, that is what Python is doing.
In fact, a lot of the Python interpreter, the program called Python,
中文字幕
is itself written in C. And so someone, just thankfully not you,
has had to write all of that functionality.
中文字幕
But Python itself is just an abstraction.
These functions are abstractions on top of these lower level implementation
中文字幕
details.
And that should really become part of your vocabulary,
中文字幕
distinguishing between design, and abstractions, and lower level
implementation details, all of which are important,
中文字幕
but they don't all need to be at the tip of your mind
when you're thinking about how to solve a problem.
中文字幕
You can solve problems at this level.
And then lower down into the implementation details.
中文字幕
So after that, we tried to tie everything together.
And we looked more generally at web programming.
中文字幕
We just looked at one paradigm of web programming, the MVC model,
so to speak.
中文字幕
There are dozens, probably more these days,
all of them with fancy confusing acronyms.
中文字幕
But it's just different ways to solve problem.
Because we humans, with each passing year,
中文字幕
realize that, hey, I, in my company, and you, in your company,
and you, in your dorm, we're all trying to solve similar ideas.
中文字幕
We're all trying to make an app.
We're all trying to make a website.
中文字幕
And we're all reinventing wheels.
And so new frameworks are invented, and new methodologies, and people
中文字幕
start sharing.
And the world starts to collaborate by way of open source tools,
中文字幕
that we, ourselves, have used, like Flask being one such example thereof,
jQuery a little bit, Bootstrap as well, all of which
中文字幕
allow us to sort of solve problems collectively
and get real, more interesting work done without having to deal with all
中文字幕
of those implementation details.
And then lastly, did we introduce one last language, SQL,
中文字幕
which gave us all the more of a back end, where
we can store stuff, a lot more stuff, and a lot
中文字幕
more easily than we could with CSVs alone.
And if you like this world of statistics, and data science,
中文字幕
and the like, or if you're going back to the world of the humanities,
or medicine, or any number of fields, where there's just lots of words,
中文字幕
lots of books, lots of texts, lots of data, ultimately, SQL,
and all of these languages can be used to help you answer questions
中文字幕
that you might have in those domains.
So from there, where do we go?
中文字幕
So after Thanksgiving break here in Cambridge is the CS50 hackathon.
It will begin at 7:00 PM in the evening, and it will end at 7:00 AM
中文字幕
the next night.
And it's meant to be one of those uniquely collegiate experiences, where
中文字幕
you have alongside you all of your friends and classmates,
and all of the course's staff into the night, working on final projects.
中文字幕
An opportunity to be productive.
An opportunity far enough away from the deadline to feel good about it
中文字幕
and to take breaks, and to have dinner with us at 9:00 PM,
to have second dinner with us around 1:00 AM.
中文字幕
And then if you're still awake, around 5:00
AM we charter some Harvard shuttles, and take ourselves
中文字幕
to IHOP for breakfast as well.
But you're welcome to go to sleep at any point in between.
中文字幕
Just to give you a sense of what it's like.
On arrival, the students from both Harvard and Yale
中文字幕
ascend the stairs, joining the staff for the evening of programming.
We have reserved the entire space above the Innovation Lab
中文字幕
across the river at HBS, where everyone will
be able to tuck themselves away into a corner with their partners,
中文字幕
or with their friends, or classmates more
generally, and just work throughout the night on their final projects.
中文字幕
There's a photo booth, and a Myla as well,
as well as other members of the staff.
中文字幕
There are therapy dogs in some years, if you'd like to take a little break
and meet such puppies as these.
中文字幕
And then, of course, at 5:00 AM, is IHOP.
And this is Maria Zlatkova, now at Facebook,
中文字幕
greeting us at last year's breakfast.
And then the CS50 fair.
中文字幕
On both campuses is this event.
An opportunity for all of you to show off
中文字幕
just what you accomplish this semester, truly meant
to be the capstone of what you've done, not exhibiting your own problems
中文字幕
sets that you were told how to build, but your own project that you yourself
decided how to.
中文字幕
We'll invite the entire campus, the faculty, students, and staff
from across campus.
中文字幕
Usually it's about 2,000-plus people.
We'll be in the beautifully renovated Smith Center this year,
中文字幕
right in Harvard Square.
So we expect to have quite a few passers by and tourists as well.
中文字幕
It's always coupled with a fabulous raffle, whereby
you'll all be given, as student presenters, little smiley face
中文字幕
stickers or such.
Anyone who chats you up and asks you about your project
中文字幕
and for a quick demo on your laptop or phone,
you'll be able to hand them a sticker and be eligible, therefore,
中文字幕
for fabulous prizes.
Along the way though, there'll be popcorn, and snacks,
中文字幕
and music, and more.
Some of our alumni from industry to talk to you
中文字幕
about the real world, and summer time, and full-time opportunities as well.
And what you'll see is a space that looks, and feels, and sounds,
中文字幕
rather like this, with folks just mingling around,
really proud and happy to see what it is that you and your friends pulled off.
中文字幕
With popcorn in attendance, stress balls in attendance, and staff, and students
alike, hopefully delighting in what it is that you did.
中文字幕
Everyone will end the semester with a I took CS50 t-shirt.
Hopefully, this is something you two will wear proud.
中文字幕
In fact, this truly is where I got my start.
1996, CS50 changed my life.
中文字幕
And, in fact-- in fact, here, is indeed proof
of just how proud I am to have actually gotten my way through this course
中文字幕
so long ago, when I, myself, had not had the nerve freshman year even to shop.
So hopefully, you feel yourselves a member of that community as well.
中文字幕
So of course, we thought we'd give you a sense of what the next few weeks might
be like, especially if you don't necessarily budget your time properly.
中文字幕
A few years ago, we used before the CS50 IDE,
the software called CS59 Appliance, which
中文字幕
was like a downloadable version of it for your Mac and PC.
It tended to be a little slower, and you'll see an allusion to that.
中文字幕
But this video produced by CS50's production team, and particularly
Dan Coffee, was CS50's first experimentation with puppetry.
中文字幕
And you'll see that we tell the story by proxy
of a CS50 student working on their final project, just as the deadline nears.
中文字幕
And so if we could dim the lights, this will
be our last of the videos for today before we now look ahead at the years
中文字幕
after.
- "MISSION IMPOSSIBLE"]
中文字幕
So our thanks to Dan Coffee and the team for producing that
as well, if we could.
中文字幕
That is indeed exactly how deadlines work.
Every time we have a deadline, I--
中文字幕
So life after 50.
So the training wheels are off, you can keep the rubber duck
中文字幕
and have someone to talk to as you wrestle with problems.
But the CS50 IDE, while you can keep using it,
中文字幕
it's not something you, odds are, going to use in the real world for very long.
And there really is no check 50 and help 50 in the real world,
中文字幕
though there are lots of humans.
They are not called TFs anymore, they're called friends and colleagues.
中文字幕
But you can lean on those folks as well.
And what we thought we'd give you is some list
中文字幕
of suggestions for next steps, so that you feel like there's offboarding.
And honestly, some of this will happen naturally
中文字幕
as you tackle your final projects, depending on the nature.
And if you take another class, or CS50 beyond this winter, or you experience
中文字幕
these things yourselves, but we thought we'd at least give you
some links in today's slides, so that you
中文字幕
have something to tinker with over Thanksgiving, or winter break,
or beyond.
中文字幕
So CS50 IDE is meant to be representative of a very
common programming environment.
中文字幕
It happens to be web based, it happens to be in our domain name.
But this idea of having a file browser of some sort,
中文字幕
and tabs where you write code, and a terminal window
with which you interact, incredibly, incredibly, common,
中文字幕
whether it's in the cloud, or more commonly for real world
software developers on your own Mac or your PC.
中文字幕
Frankly, some years from now, this will probably be the way it is, none of us
use our Mac, PCs per se, everything probably is remotely.
中文字幕
So odds are, at some point in the future, we'll come full circle.
But for now, it's quite common to replicate this kind
中文字幕
of setup on your own Mac or PC.
So how do you go about having a command line, which hopefully you've gleaned,
中文字幕
while frustrating, is more powerful than only having
menus and icons available to you that someone else,
中文字幕
like a company, like Microsoft or Apple has given you.
Well, in both Macs and PCs, can you install the same tools
中文字幕
that we used this semester, Clang, and Make,
and you get CD, and LS, and [? Miktor, ?] and all of those commands
中文字幕
on both Mac OS or Windows.
And the starting points can be here.
中文字幕
Both of those provide their own sort of terminal windows, and the software
therein.
中文字幕
You can just install via those two starting points.
Now what about Git?
中文字幕
You've seen or heard about Git, even though we
don't use it hands on in the class.
中文字幕
Odds are you will use this in higher level CS courses, if you take it.
It's one of the most popular programs with which
中文字幕
to save versions of your software.
Now you may have noticed the CS50 IDE does this automatically for you.
中文字幕
You can go to File, Revision History, and you can kind of
go back and forth in time.
中文字幕
And that's great and wonderfully useful, but it doesn't really lend itself
to collaborating with others.
中文字幕
And so, if you're working with partners for the final project,
in the simplest form, you can just have one of you
中文字幕
share your CS50 IDE with the other user names.
And you'll all just share the same account.
中文字幕
And that's fine.
But it gets a little annoying and complicated
中文字幕
if you're both trying to edit the same files,
you're not necessarily talking to one another, or you're in different rooms.
中文字幕
Like, at some point you want to have good workflows.
And so via this URL here, does Brian introduce you to Git, a command line
中文字幕
tool that's super, super, super popular these days, that lets
you save versions of your code.
中文字幕
So you no longer call it Mario 1.C, and Mario 2.C,
and Mario 3 AM.C and the like.
中文字幕
You actually call it Mario.C.
But you let Git take care of time-stamping it and versioning it
中文字幕
for you.
And Git allows you to share your code in the cloud.
中文字幕
What we use GitHub for is for, of course, submissions, and such,
and for commenting.
中文字幕
But more generally, it's used for just storing
code and sharing with other people.
中文字幕
So what you'll do with Git is literally Git
push it to a service like a GitHub, or GitLabs, or others.
中文字幕
Where someone else can then Git pull it onto their own Mac or PC.
And, therefore, you're sharing files.
中文字幕
You don't email.
You don't Dropbox, or the like.
中文字幕
You actually use a standardized software tool.
You can install it via these instructions
中文字幕
here, if you don't have it already.
And more usefully too, can you sign up for free repositories
中文字幕
GitHub.com, you already have an account.
Since you have a student ID, you can go to this URL
中文字幕
here and tell them you're a student at Harvard, or Yale, or beyond.
And then say, can I please have free private repos,
中文字幕
so you can keep your own personal or school projects private,
without needing access to CS50's own organization.
中文字幕
So what do you write code in?
So, there's bunches of editors these days.
中文字幕
Among the most popular is a tools that's called
Atom, which is an open source text editor that
中文字幕
has lots and lots of plug-ins.
This is like the tabbed windows for writing code.
中文字幕
It does syntax, highlighting, and so much more,
so that your code is easy to edit, and it looks pretty wild
中文字幕
you're working on it, and just makes life pretty easy.
Also super popular these days is VS Code or Visual Studio Code.
中文字幕
They are functionally pretty much equivalent.
You can ask your teaching fellows or friends which you prefer,
中文字幕
or just try them both.
They are free, and there's dozens of other options.
中文字幕
These two just currently have a lot of momentum in industry.
Within the terminal window, though, is what a lot of CS students would use,
中文字幕
something called Vim.
And there's alternatives there, called [? Emax ?] and a few others.
中文字幕
But Vim is actually what I grew up on, and still to this day tend to use.
I tend not to use a GUI.
中文字幕
I just use a bigger terminal window with lots and lots of code inside of it.
And Vim is more of a command line tool, where
中文字幕
you have to memorize keyboard shortcuts more so,
but it's also more powerful in the same way
中文字幕
a terminal window tends to be as well.
So whatever you are most comfortable with is fine.
中文字幕
So suppose you want to post a website, like your own personal home
page, your resume, an artistic portfolio, or whatnot,
中文字幕
where do you even begin?
You can certainly make it on your Mac or PC in an HTML file,
中文字幕
but no one in the world can access it.
You can put it in CS50 IDE, but that goes
中文字幕
to sleep eventually, when you're not using it,
which makes it hard for people on the internet to visited at any hour.
中文字幕
But fortunately, there's so many free services out there,
at least if you have modest usage.
中文字幕
If you're trying to build a business, odds
are you're going to pay someone for the bandwidth, and the support,
中文字幕
and so forth.
But if you just have a home page, where you're getting dozens, hundreds, maybe
中文字幕
low thousands of visits, which is probably
likely the case for personal sites, you can
中文字幕
use something called GitHub Pages, a free service where you store your HTML
files, JavaScript, and CSS on GitHub.com,
中文字幕
and they host it for you for free.
Netlify is another free one too, and dot, dot, dot,
中文字幕
you can Google ad nauseam and find any number of free such services.
These just tend to be two popular ones with which I too am familiar.
中文字幕
Hosting a web app, so not a static website, but something more dynamic,
we'll have instructions that we'll circulate for this final project
中文字幕
as well, so that you can sort of graduate from CS50 IDE
and run your final project, or your website,
中文字幕
or your student group's tool, or your startup's website
on a third-party service.
中文字幕
Heroku tends to be very popular.
They too have a free tier of service.
中文字幕
So long as your website's not being hammered by lots and lots of users,
you can use it for free.
中文字幕
You get free access to a database, something called Post [? Gress, ?]
which we alluded to earlier in the semester,
中文字幕
using the same data types we discussed.
Wix is another common one too, that very recently launched support for code, not
中文字幕
just static web sites too.
So these are starting points.
中文字幕
But certainly use Google or the like to find other options as well.
Then there's infrastructure, as a service, so to speak.
中文字幕
There's some bigger fish out there, Amazon, and Microsoft, and Google,
that have cloud-based services.
中文字幕
The learning curve tends to be a little higher, frankly.
So I would encourage you to maybe start with the previous examples, which
中文字幕
are businesses built on top of these layers.
But if you're interested, absolutely sign up
中文字幕
as a student for any number of these services,
and they tend to give you lots of financial credits,
中文字幕
so you can just try things for free, for like a month,
or a year, or whatnot to get your feet wet.
中文字幕
It's a wonderfully free world when you're just
getting started in this space.
中文字幕
And then more general advice.
Read lots.
中文字幕
And I'm sure if you ask the TFs and CAs, you'll
get an even longer list of sites.
中文字幕
But these tend to be the kinds of sites I go to if I just kind of want
to stay in the loop on things.
中文字幕
Subscribing to various sub-Reddits, so to speak,
is compelling, where information, news, conversations, just get pushed at you.
中文字幕
And honestly, whenever I'm asked how I kind of stay
in touch with certain things, I hear things from friends,
中文字幕
I get emails about technologies, I get curious, and so I poke around.
And these tend to be the places that I might go, and a lot of tech people
中文字幕
go, to talk about new trends and technologies.
Or if you're trying to vet something, should I use x or should I use y,
中文字幕
don't just use Google.
Check out those websites as well.
中文字幕
And then CS50, if you'd like to stay in touch.
So CS50, not so much here on campus, but for students around the world,
中文字幕
maintains a number of online communities, all of which
you're welcome to partake in, answering questions, or asking questions,
中文字幕
or the like.
And those are just the few of the current ones now.
中文字幕
Any questions on any or all of those past or future steps?
Anything at all?
中文字幕
No?
All right.
中文字幕
OK, so we'll adjourn in just a little bit
time for our tradition of cake downstairs in the pub.
中文字幕
But we also have one other tradition, especially now
that you have some 10 weeks of experience behind you.
中文字幕
For all intents and purposes, you are all now
qualified as CS50 staff, because, indeed, at the end of the day,
中文字幕
most of CS50 staff are recent alumni of the course themselves,
sophomores, juniors, seniors, recent graduates, students online who
中文字幕
have taken this class, maybe taken another class in the spring or beyond,
and then joined us as staff.
中文字幕
So realize that even if you're not feeling more comfortable yet,
or most comfortable, nor are most of the staff,
中文字幕
and myself included, with a lot of these things.
And so long as you stay one step ahead and you know the kinds of resources
中文字幕
to turn to, this is what it really is about when learning in this world.
And in fact, a very common mindset, I do know, in the class,
中文字幕
in the problem sets, in the quiz, is wait a minute,
you didn't teach us this.
中文字幕
And that, odds are, was quite true quite often.
And I don't just mean to be rationalizing it.
中文字幕
That was very much by design.
In the real world, that's exactly the emotion you're hopefully going to feel,
中文字幕
or realistically going to feel quite often.
And we truly do hope that among the tools you've gotten,
中文字幕
training wheels and beyond, is to know where to have the right instincts now
with how to bootstrap yourself, so to speak, and solve problems, and learn
中文字幕
things on your own.
But we thought we would, in conclusion put that to the test.
中文字幕
And I think for this, we need--
let's see, we have a bunch of chairs up here, four student volunteers,
中文字幕
for about to be--
four about to be alumni volunteers.
中文字幕
OK, over here in the front, yeah, come on down.
Over here, in the front, and three.
中文字幕
And let me try to see about four, over here, come on down.
All right four, you have four?
中文字幕
Colton's going to join us.
Uh-oh, OK, we'll take five, that's fine, but you gotta bring a chair.
中文字幕
We'll find a chair somewhere.
Come on down.
中文字幕
And now I need four staff volunteers, if we could.
Who on the staff might--
中文字幕
Oh, yes, ma'am come on up.
Athena has volunteered.
中文字幕
Oh, Erin, would you like to--
oh, come up.
中文字幕
Yeah, who?
OK, yeah, come on up, Robert.
中文字幕
OK, thank you so much for volunteering.
OK, so-- but the catch is, we need the staff on their own team.
中文字幕
So let's put the students here, because you need--
that's OK.
中文字幕
Could you guys go over here?
OK, all five of you-- we have our student team over here.
中文字幕
And we'll find you one more chair in just a moment.
Staff, go ahead and take a seat here.
中文字幕
You each have a piece of paper, a pen, and a microphone.
And why don't we go ahead, as we get ready to go here--
中文字幕
do you want to each just say hello and introduce yourself?
ERIN: Hello.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Well, you can tell them.
ERIN: Hello, I'm Erin, one of the course preceptors.
中文字幕
ISAAC: I'm Isaac, I'm a TF.
ROBERT: I'm Robert, I'm a CA.
中文字幕
ATHENA: And I'm Athena, I'm a TF.
ANDREA: Hi, I'm Andrea, I'm an alumni, soon.
中文字幕
AVIVA: Hi, I'm Aviva, me too.
JONATHAN: I'm Jonathan.
中文字幕
APRIL: April.
ERIC: I'm Eric.
中文字幕
COLTON: Hi, I Colton, I'm a technologist.
SPEAKER 1: All right, so what are we all doing up here, you might wonder.
中文字幕
Well, we have this tradition of using all of those questions
that you offered for the quiz, recall in problem set seven, just a couple
中文字幕
of weeks ago, as refreshers.
Now mind you, there is quite the difference between, I think,
中文字幕
a lot of the questions you offered up at suggestions for quiz questions.
Many of them were like, what is two in binary,
中文字幕
or maybe what is three in binary.
And so, that was great.
中文字幕
But we were looking for a little harder questions.
And we get some of those too.
中文字幕
And so Colton kindly went through the thousands
of questions that were submitted just a couple of weeks
中文字幕
ago, to pluck out some of the most serious, some of the most playful ones.
And I have here them clustered into categories,
中文字幕
because we have this tradition of playing our own version, staff
versus students, of Jeopardy.
中文字幕
Now because you all wrote the questions in the form of questions,
I'm going to read them in the form of questions and not answers.
中文字幕
So it's more of a quiz show, if we could, staff versus students.
The first person to raise their hand, we'll call on first.
中文字幕
We don't have buzzer technology here.
Colton will be our judge, if you don't mind being the judge.
中文字幕
And we'll do just a few rounds of single and double,
and on Final Jeopardy, followed by cake.
中文字幕
So in a moment, we'll show you the categories,
and begin asking the questions.
中文字幕
Do you have any questions of your own?
STUDENT: Are we answering with questions?
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: You will be answering as an answer.
I'll ask the questions, you answer.
中文字幕
So it's not really Jeopardy, but it just kind of sounds better
if we call it Jeopardy.
中文字幕
OK, so-- and also, also, look at what we made in HTML to facilitate this.
Let's zoom in.
中文字幕
Here we go, Enhance, whoo-hoo, look at those HTML tables and links.
OK, so without further ado, I think before today began,
中文字幕
we decided that the students had won the coin toss.
Would you like to pick a category, and then I'll
中文字幕
ask you a question in that category.
STUDENT: Scratch for 1,000.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Scratch-- for $100?
STUDENT: No, there's no $100.
中文字幕
STUDENT: $1,000.
SPEAKER 1: Oh, I heard 1,000.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Yeah, 1,000.
SPEAKER 1: OK, so week--
中文字幕
week zero, week zero, the question is what institution develop Scratch.
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Colton?
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Whoever raises their hand first.
COLTON: [INAUDIBLE]
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: OK, OK, students.
STUDENT: MIT.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: MIT is the correct answer for 1,000 points.
Very nicely done.
中文字幕
OK, if no one's going to clap--
SPEAKER 1: There we go.
中文字幕
No it's OK.
We have an HTML button for that too.
中文字幕
All right, so students, you have control.
What would you like?
中文字幕
STUDENT: Scratch for 800.
STUDENT: Yeah, I was--
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Scratch for what?
STUDENT: All the Scratch ones.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Scratch for 800.
SPEAKER 1: Scratch for 800, working our way through the Scratch questions.
中文字幕
OK, what color is the cat?
Students--
中文字幕
STUDENT: Orange.
SPEAKER 1: Orange, OK, now funny enough, two people asked this question
中文字幕
in P Set 7, and we got two answers--
yellow and orange.
中文字幕
Perhaps by a show of hands-- yellow--
orange.
中文字幕
OK, orange, students get the $800.
Very nicely done.
中文字幕
Students--
STUDENT: We should do something big.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Don't do C. I'm terrible with C.
STUDENT: Arrays.
中文字幕
STUDENT: No.
STUDENT: Arrays are easy.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Fine.
STUDENT: Fine, arrays.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Arrays for 1,000.
SPEAKER 1: Arrays for 1,000.
中文字幕
So this is from week two for 1,000.
This is going to be--
中文字幕
what is the running time of merge sort?
Staff?
中文字幕
STAFF: End log in.
SPEAKER 1: End log in is correct for a 1,000.
中文字幕
STUDENT: [INAUDIBLE]
SPEAKER 1: Staff, what would you like.
中文字幕
STAFF: Memory.
SPEAKER 1: Memory for--
中文字幕
STAFF: 1,000.
SPEAKER 1: For a 1,000?
中文字幕
STAFF: Yeah.
SPEAKER 1: OK, for 1,000, what is the name of the tool you
中文字幕
can run to see if your program--
staff?
中文字幕
STAFF: Valgrind.
SPEAKER 1: If your program has memory leaks, Valgrind is correct, for 1,000.
中文字幕
STAFF: [INAUDIBLE]
STAFF: That was nice.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Staff for 1,000, what do you want next?
STAFF: Week Star, what is that?
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Oh, week star is the wild card, so you can get any week.
STAFF: Week Star for 1,000.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Week Star for 1,000.
So I shall choose the category to be--
中文字幕
what is rubber duck debugging?
What is rubber duck debugging?
中文字幕
Students?
STUDENT: I'll answer it.
中文字幕
It's when you read every line of code to a rubber
duck and to try and find a mistake.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: I think that's correct.
Very well done for 1,000.
中文字幕
All right, I think we have time for one more question in single Jeopardy.
Students you have control and the lead.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Go for the lowest possible [INAUDIBLE]..
STUDENT: No, why don't we try Week for 800, or C for--
中文字幕
STUDENT: For like 200, because then they can't catch up.
STUDENT: So 200.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Yeah.
SPEAKER 1: Students?
中文字幕
STUDENT: C for 200.
SPEAKER 1: For what?
中文字幕
STUDENT: C for 200.
SPEAKER 1: C for-- whoa, OK.
中文字幕
C for 200 in week one.
Week 1-- your question is going to be--
中文字幕
is C the absolute worst?
Students, for 200?
中文字幕
STUDENT: OK, I think it's not, because--
STUDENT: The person asking that would say, yes,
中文字幕
so we just have to match their answer.
STUDENT: We have to match their answer?
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: The correct answers are right here.
STUDENT: Yes.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: No.
This is what I'm told.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Yes.
SPEAKER 1: I hear two yeses and one no.
中文字幕
STUDENT: I stick by my opinion.
STUDENT: Majority wins.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: The answer is yes, it is the worst.
STUDENT: Yes.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: For 200.
OK, so we're now moving on to Double Jeopardy,
中文字幕
where all the dollar values are doubled and the categories
have changed two later weeks, still with one wild card.
中文字幕
Students.
STUDENT: Oh, god.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Python for 2,000.
SPEAKER 1: For 2,000.
中文字幕
STUDENT: I'm sorry, I just made that decision.
STUDENT: Python, 2,000.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: What week?
STUDENT: Python, 2,000.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Python for 2,000.
So that's week six.
中文字幕
Python for 2,000, and a question that a classmate asked was,
what is an animal that you don't want to find under your pillow that shares
中文字幕
its name with a programming language?
Students.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Python snake.
A python snake.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Python is correct, yes, for $2,000.
Very nice.
中文字幕
Students, Python 6,000.
SPEAKER 1: Time for just a few questions before we move on to final.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Oh, let's do, like Web--
do you guys want to do Web--
中文字幕
STUDENT: Sure, Web 2,000.
SPEAKER 1: Web for 2,000, that was week seven.
中文字幕
And a question here was, who is your friend?
STUDENT: What?
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Students for 2,000.
Oh, did you see Erin first?
中文字幕
Sorry, Colton's the judge.
STAFF: Developer tools?
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: I'm sorry, that's incorrect.
Yes, students?
中文字幕
STUDENT: Inspect Elements?
STUDENT: Inspect Elements.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Inspect Element, also incorrect, I'm afraid.
Students, again?
中文字幕
STUDENT: A rubber duck.
SPEAKER 1: A rubber duck is incorrect.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Google.
SPEAKER 1: Google, no.
中文字幕
I think you're negative 8,000 now.
But that's OK, we won't deduct.
中文字幕
We won't deduct, it's fine.
I know that's not how Jeopardy's played.
中文字幕
OK.
STAFF: W3 Schools?
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: W3 Schools, incorrect.
Students-- What?
中文字幕
STUDENT: David [INAUDIBLE]?
SPEAKER 1: No, not him.
中文字幕
Yeah?
STUDENT: Stack Exchange?
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: What?
STUDENT: Stack Exchange?
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Not Stack Exchange.
The answer is Bootstrap.
中文字幕
OK, moving on.
So time for two more questions in Double Jeopardy.
中文字幕
The students I think had control, right?
STUDENT: Yeah.
中文字幕
STUDENT: What do you guys want to do?
SPEAKER 1: Staff need to pull ahead here.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Just like any for week for 2,000.
STUDENT: Wild card 2,000?
中文字幕
STUDENT: Week [INAUDIBLE] for 2,000.
STUDENT: Wild card, 2,000.
中文字幕
STUDENT: Wild card for 2,000.
Audience, what week shall we give them?
中文字幕
One through seven, 0 through 7.
Four, I heard.
中文字幕
Week four.
Week four-- what is the code for OK?
中文字幕
Staff?
STAFF: 200.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: 200 for 2,000.
All right, so staff have control.
中文字幕
We have time for one more question before we move on to Final Jeopardy.
STAFF: [INAUDIBLE]
中文字幕
STAFF: No, we want to be able to be in touch with it, right?
Data structures, 1,200.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Data structures for 1,200.
Data structures for 1,200.
中文字幕
And that was, what week was that?
Four, that's week four.
中文字幕
What do you call the situation when a structure
refers to itself in its definition?
中文字幕
Students?
STUDENT: Recursion.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: Recursion is correct for $1,200, very nice.
OK, so we now go into our last question of CS50 of staff versus students.
中文字幕
Staff have 4,000, students have 6,200.
You're about to be told the Final Jeopardy category, at which point
中文字幕
each team needs to commit in writing, on the sheet of paper in front of them,
with the CS50 pen in front of them, to a dollar amount,
中文字幕
keeping in mind that you will either gain or lose this amount.
All right, go ahead and choose your-- oh,
中文字幕
here we go, the category for Final Jeopardy is going to be Buggy.
Buggy will be your category.
中文字幕
Any dollar amount.
OK, so, so, here we go.
中文字幕
The question is, they've all committed to a dollar amount.
OK, I feel like you can hedge your bets there.
中文字幕
All right, so here we go, Final Jeopardy, Buggy is the category.
In which state, besides Massachusetts, does Google sometimes think we reside?
中文字幕
[MUSIC PLAYING - "JEOPARDY THEME SONG"]
All right.
中文字幕
So, I think staff were not in the lead, or not in the lead,
so we start with you.
中文字幕
Staff, first of all, how much did you wager?
OK, depending, I think, on how the question went,
中文字幕
they wagered either $4,000 or $40, apparently.
STAFF: [INAUDIBLE]
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: $40, will go with 4,000.
And what was your answer?
中文字幕
STAFF: We picked Kansas.
SPEAKER 1: Kansas, interesting.
中文字幕
Now, students, how much did you wager?
STUDENT: 2,000.
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: 2,000.
and what was your answer?
中文字幕
STUDENT: Also Kansas.
SPEAKER 1: And also Kansas.
中文字幕
So 2,000 would bring you to 8,200.
4,000 would bring you to 8,000.
中文字幕
So if you're both right, students you might have clinched it.
Does the audience remember where Google thought
中文字幕
we were a few weeks ago, despite the fact that I
misstated where Google thinks we were?
中文字幕
Oklahoma was my incorrect answer, it turns out.
Wyoming, also incorrect.
中文字幕
But we can do sort of binary search in that area.
Anyone at all?
中文字幕
SPEAKER 1: It is, in fact, Kansas.
So congratulations to the students' team.
中文字幕
A round of applause, if we could, for our students.
Thank you so much for joining us in CS50.
中文字幕
We are so proud of you all, cannot wait to see you at the fair.
Cake is now served downstairs.
中文字幕
And my thanks again to the staff.